Friends, health insurance is a very good
facility if used properly,
but there are many questions and problems regarding it.
Many people often think
in the comments
that the policy is not good, this company is
not happy with paying the claim, so what is the reason for that? The basic
problem, that is, the fundamental
problem, is some such
questions that
everyone has, why are the money deducted from the claim?
We file the entire claim,
and when the company pays the claim, it
deducts some money from us,
due to which we are not happy. The
second question that comes from the insurance company is why is the claim rejected?
Now we
take the patient to the hospital in an emergency
and we think that the insurance company will pay
us the claim, so let's face the problem of the disease,
but we will not face any financial problems in the future, then
why does that problem arise? And the
third question is that if we also
doubt in our mind that I have
bought the wrong policy or have I
bought the policy from the wrong company? The
most important reason behind all these questions is the
health insurance plan or
policy that we have.  Now, if we
buy the wrong plan or the wrong policy,
whose money is invested in it? Who has invested it with
their hard-earned money?
You and I have made this claim with our own money.
Whose claim will be rejected or will
money be deducted from it? It's obvious that when
we are the policy holders, our patient was admitted, so the
claim also has a direct relation to us.
And whose responsibility is it to
understand, think, and analyze the plans before
buying them? This is also our responsibility, friends. No
one else is going to be affected by this.
Now, understand insurance policy
plans is quite complex, and
we have come up with a solution to this problem of yours. We
bring you videos of health insurance plans in very simple language.
Today, we have brought a video of one such plan,
which is called HDFC Ego Optima
Restore. Hello friends, my name is
Ravindra Singh, and I welcome you to the
DSC Solutions YouTube channel. Here,
you will get all the information related to insurance,
that too in very simple language and
free of course, that is, without any cost.
Let's start the video without
wasting any time.  Friends, in today's video we will
learn about HDFC EGO Optima Restore
Plan. If you watch this video
till the complete end, then you will understand all the
terms and conditions and
coverage about it. Using a health
insurance policy is like
driving a car or using a phone.
If you understand all its features and benefits and
know how to use it properly, then
you will never be disappointed. So, what will
we learn in today's video? What is the
restore benefit in HDFC and Optima Restore Plan?
How big is this benefit
that the plan itself is named '
Restore'. Secondly, we will learn what is the multiplayer
benefit? What are the benefits in this plan? What are the
things being multiplied, that is,
which things can you benefit from many times?
Thirdly, we will learn all
its benefits and coverage, that is, all the
treatments covered under it, which
facilities you will get one by one. I will
tell you with examples and
explain how you will get all these
benefits.  And the coverage has to be done.
How to get the fourth discount. Now, all these things will definitely be available,
but I will also tell you
how to buy this policy at the lowest price.
And at the
end of the video, I will also tell you about the exclusions.
See, there are some treatments which the
insurance policy will never cover, and many
times we assume that they are covered
and expect their related treatment. If it
ever comes up, we will include it in the policy. So,
I will tell you about all the exclusions
which this policy will never cover. So
friends, by the
end of the video, if you want to buy a good health insurance policy and
especially an Optima Restore plan, then
you should definitely watch this video. So
friends, the most
important feature of the plan, on which the plan is
named, is the restore benefit. Let's
understand that feature. What does restore benefit
mean? It has several names.
Different plans give this feature different
names. Like you might have heard about
refill, recharge, loan statement. These are all
similar names. They mean the same thing as benefit.
What is that benefit? If you look at it,  If any
amount of basic sum is
deducted for any of these treatments, then it
restores that amount again, that is,
recharges it. How much will it restore?
Now, you can say hundred percent of basic
sum shown, that is, if you have
taken a health insurance plan of Rs 10 lakh
and it gets exhausted completely, then
after that, if you file a health insurance claim, then
this amount will be
restored again and the previous Rs 10 lakh will be
ready for you. Any member of your family
can redeem that amount.
Thirdly,
in both the cases,
it will be restored after the total exhaustion. As I
told you earlier, even if you have redeemed all the Rs 10 lakh,
it will still be ready for the next Rs 10 lakh. Even
if you redeemed Rs 3 lakh out of Rs 10,
it will recharge or
restore it again and make the entire Rs 10 lakh
ready for any next claim.
But there is a condition in this that any
single claim, that is, a claim comes, that is your
basic sum.  It will not give more than the insured, that is,
if your policy is a health
insurance plan, suppose it is
of Rs 10 lakh and a single claim is made
of Rs 12 or 15 lakh, then this additional Rs 10 lakh will
not be deducted from it, you will
get a maximum claim of Rs 10 lakh only,
but because that basic insurance is completely
over, your
restore benefit of Rs 10 lakh will be
ready for the next claim, the single claim limit will
not exceed Rs 10 lakh,
in the case of restore benefit, now friends, the second
important benefit in this is called
multiply benefit, that is, your
benefit is getting multiplied in this, so let us
understand this, see, whenever we buy a health
insurance policy, then
after the completion of the whole year, the insurance company
says that if you have not taken any claim in this previous year, then
we will give you some additional
benefit, so here the insurance
company calls it multiply benefit,
how much is this  You will get the benefit of 50% of the
sum insured for every claim-free year, which means that in the
year in which you do not make a claim, then your sum insured will increase by 50% of
your basic sum insured in the next
year. For example,
if you have a basic sum insured of ₹10 lakh
and you do not make a claim for the entire year, then
from the next year, your sum insured of ₹15 lakh will be
updated in your policy.
Now what is the maximum limit for this, till when will it
increase? Suppose you did not make a claim continuously for 5 years,
but it will only go up to a maximum of
100% of the sum insured, which
means from ₹10 lakh, it will increase only up to ₹20 lakh.
This amount will not increase beyond that,
i.e. 50% in the first year and 50% in the second year.
Your amount will multiply and double in two years, that is
why it is
called multiplier benefit. Suppose your sum has doubled,
after that if you make a claim
in the third year, then it will also reduce
in the same ratio.  It will not happen that as soon as you take a claim,
it will return from ₹20 lakh to ₹10 lakh.
If a claim comes, then it will return from ₹20 lakh to ₹15 lakh, that is, it will
reduce by only 50%. In many plans, as soon as a
claim comes, this multiplier benefit
or no-claim policy or cumulative bonus becomes zero and
you are left with only the basic time.
But in this plan, it is
50% which is quite good, it is a very high
amount. Your time gets reduced in 2 years
and if a claim is made then it will
reduce. Now in this ratio, it is
called multiplier benefit. Now friends,
after understanding the two major benefits, now we know
all its coverage and benefits, that is,
we know what are the standard features that you will get in the policy and what are the coverages.
The first is what are the options of the same insured, that is, with how much
time left can you buy the policy? The
minimum will start from ₹3 lakh
and the maximum will go up to ₹50 lakh.  You are seeing options
300, 50000,
150000, 25 lakh and 50 lakh. In this you can buy family
floater i.e. plan for the entire family and
if you want to buy it for any individual then
individual policy can also be
bought from the insured options at this time.
Next comes the matter of entry for further
policy. Minimum and maximum entry for taking the policy.
See what is next. In this,
any individual or family member starting from 91 days to 65 years
can buy this policy. Now comes the matter of dependent child i.e. the one
who will come in this policy with his parents,
his maximum further period is 25
years i.e. for 25 years he can stay in
this policy with his parents with the premium of such child.
Now friends let's talk about
renewal.
You can stay in this policy at any time.
I have told you the limits
but you
can get it renewed for continuous life long provided you have not violated any term
and condition which is against all the terms and conditions of the company.
If you fulfill the terminated condition fully,
you
can avail the renewal benefit for the entire lifetime. Next
comes room rent. Whenever we
admit a patient to the hospital
for treatment, he is assigned a room
category by the hospital.
So, we have to choose the room rent,
whether we choose a single private room
or we can also choose shared accommodation, that is,
two patients can stay in one room.
Even in the general ward, we often
keep a patient for some minor treatment or if we want a
higher category of rooms like deluxe
showroom or deluxe suites, then we can choose that room too. So, there is
no such capping that you have to
take a room of any specific category. You
can take a room of any category as long as the
sum insured remains in your policy. Next
point is pre and post
hospitalization. Friends, these are the expenses
that we incur before admission.
We go to the doctor, get tests done, take medicines
and when we don't get relief, then we are forced to get
admitted and even
after discharge, the same thing happens that recovery takes so much
time because there are so many
medicines, the doctor tracks the
progress through tests, there are a lot of expenses in that too, so the company will bear
such expenses that you have incurred 60 days before admission i.e. till two months ago
and all the
expenses that you have incurred till 180 days after discharge
in this plan, provided the
insurance company has
passed and approved the claim for the treatment for which you were admitted, only then these expenses will be approved for
you. Now, this cannot be cashless
because
you have already paid this money to the doctor, paid the test person,
paid the medicine person, so
you will have to take all this
in the reimbursement claim, that is, after
submitting their documents and invoice to the insurance company, that money will be returned
to your account, I told you, we
save your claim from getting approved.  For
whatever treatment you are admitted for,
then you can get these expenses covered under Bhimber. Now
friends, the next benefit comes
domiciliary hospitalization, that is, if the patient
gets treatment at home, then that is also covered under it, but
it is not that if the patient ever says that
I want treatment at home, then that will
not be covered. There are some terms and
conditions in this, if the doctor says that you should
get treatment at home or there is
no availability of beds in the hospital or the
patient is not in such a condition that he
can go to the hospital, then this treatment will be covered.
Next comes day care treatment,
friends, this is such a treatment in which the
patient is treated within two to four hours and is
discharged because you
know that for a simple hospital claim, it is
necessary for the patient to be admitted in a hospital for at least 24 hours, but if it is any
day treatment and he gets discharged within two to four
hours, then
all such treatments will also be covered by
Optima Restore Plan's policy. Next
comes ambulance cover. Now see, if the
patient ever has to go in an emergency, then by
ambulance will he go?  If you go,
how much will you get for the ambulance? ₹2000 per
hospital, that is, whenever you have to be admitted, the
hospital will be covered for ₹2000. Sometimes this happens
in big cities to metro cities.
If your sum insured is up to ₹500000,
that is, you have not taken any option between three and five lakh rupees, then
you will not get this air ambulance coverage in it.
But if your sum insured is in
any option between Rs 10 lakh to 50 lakh, then the
company will also give you coverage for hospital air ambulance at 2.5 lakh.
Friends, sometimes it also happens that
some part of the patient's body does not work and it becomes
necessary to replace it. If the
insurance company approves this claim, then
organ donor transplant is also
covered in it. All the treatments are covered in it. There is
no limit in it. Now everything is insured, you
can take this coverage. Next friends,
modern treatment means
many types of robotic surgeries, stem cell
therapy, that is, the technology is quite
advanced, those treatments are also included in it.  All
your modern
treatments will be covered. Next is health checkup.
Every insurance company
definitely provides the option of health checkup in its plans.
After any clean air, you can get
your family or your individual
health checkup done up to this much amount. What are those
limits? If the SAM
is insured for ₹300000, then there is no limit for health checkup in it.
If your basic SAM
is insured for ₹2500000 for 5 lakhs, then you can get tests done up to ₹5000 in it.
You can also get them done in their panel labs
and if you get it done
in any independent lab, then
you can get that expense reversed. There
is a limit of ₹8000 for 15 lakhs
and if you are insured from 20 lakhs to 50 lakhs, then
you can get tests done up to ₹10000 after every clean free air.
Next, friends, in this feature is
shed accommodation daily.  Look at the cash, the company
says that you can take a room of any category,
they have no problem in this
because there is no capping of room rent in it,
but if you
want it on your own because you have come here for
treatment, this is
not a picnic spot, the hospital, if you want to
take shared accommodation, that is, you can
stay with some other patient as well, there is no
problem in that, then the
insurance company gives you an
extra manifest pass in return
because the insurance company is also
saving money which they have to pay to the extra hospital,
what are those limits for your individual room, if your
time is insured up to Rs 15 lakh, then you will get
Rs 800 per day, maximum Rs 4800, that is,
if your hospitalization is for four days
and you
take shared accommodation and stay with someone else, during
this time you will get Rs 800 per day, maximum Rs
4800. Now if your time is from Rs 20
lakh to Rs 50 lakh, then this amount
increases from Rs 800 to Rs 1000 per  The
maximum amount will be up to Rs 6000 per day. Even
if you wait for 15 days, you will still get Rs 6000.
But if you wait for three days,
you will get Rs 3000 and Rs 2400. Now
friends, you all know that
after taking a health insurance policy, not every treatment is
covered from the first day. If it were so, then
after any problem, you would have
taken a health insurance policy and got your treatment done.
But the time after how many days this treatment is covered is
called waiting period.
Now for the statement of what are the waiting periods in this policy,
accidents are covered from the first day itself. The
time you bought the policy, your
coverage starts. Your accident is
covered from that time itself. If any treatment
comes related to the accident, then the company will
give you its claim. Second comes sickness,
illness or Covid, like now Covid treatment
comes, many times it comes due to sewing,
any kind of fever, infections,
dengue, malaria, chikungunya, all the fevers that are
Covid, all these will be covered after 30 days i.e.
If you have bought the policy today, then
after a month from that you can file a claim for any of these.
Third comes
slow growing disease or illness. There are many
diseases which take
some time to develop, 2 years, 3 years,
like there can be any kind of stone,
someone has kidney stone or
appendix, hernia, these types of
diseases take time to develop, the
company will cover these after 2 years,
if you file any claim before that, then that
claim gets rejected. Fourth comes
friends, pre-existing diseases, these are those
problems which the patient has at the time of buying the policy
and we declare that
brother, we have this problem today, you should check the
approval and issue our policy. If the
company shows the policy, then these problems
which you declare at that time will be covered
after the 3 year continuous policy period, that is, you will keep the continuous policy
period continuing for 3 years, after that if any
disease related to these comes, any
treatment comes, then that company will take care of you.  The claim will be
approved. Now, the maximum
reasons for claim rejection
come up more in these because no one
understands after how many days which
treatment is required. If you ask the policyholder at the
time of purchase and file the claim before that, then
that treatment will not be covered and the claim gets rejected. The
insurance company has all this
time which is
mentioned in your policy document, so no one can
challenge it. It is only
our responsibility to know these time
limits so that we can use them
properly and
file our claim according to these time limits. Now
friends, we have known all the benefits and coverage,
understood all the features of the policy.
Now let's come to the most important issue,
that is the price of this policy, that is, how much will
you get for the policy, you will
find it in your premium chart,
but I will tell you
how you can get a discount on that premium
so that this policy costs you the least. So, the
first point is that
you will get a discount of 7.5%
if you are a single citizen.  If you buy a two-year policy
together, then this discount will be
flat for you, but keep one thing in mind,
this will be on the second year's premium, i.e.
₹10,000. If your premium for this year is
₹10,000 and for the next year too,
you will get a 7.30 percent discount on the second year's premium of ₹10,000. The
second discount category is the
Stay Active Benefit.
It ensures that all its policy holders remain
fit. In return, it will
give you some discount. What they do for this is that all the
policy holders have to download the
health insurance company's app and
they note down the step counts in it, that is, the more
active you are, the
higher your step count will be.
You will be given a discount on that basis. So, the
slab in this is visible here.
If your step count is 5,000 or
below, then
no discount is displayed. This is a matter of annual premium
and for those between 5,000 and 8,000.  If your
step count is in between then you will get a 2%
discount on the annual premium. If the step count
is between 8000 to 10000 then you will get a 5%
discount and if your step count is
10000 or above then you will get an 8% discount
on the annual premium. Here,
7.5% was available for buying a two-year policy
but here you are
getting an 8% discount just for being active and at the same time
if you walk so many steps then you will automatically get upset a
lot. So
how will these counts be counted in this?
In individual, it is for the individual i.e.
if only one person has bought the policy then only his
step counts will be measured
but if it is a family floater plan
i.e. the entire family has bought the policy then the
average of the step counts of the adults in it will be taken into account in this.
Suppose there are two parents i.e.
husband wife and their two children then the
step count of the husband and wife will be taken into account.  After taking
out the average and applying it in this lab, that
discount will be given in it. There is one more condition, to
get this step benefit,
you have to download this app and
register in it within 30 days of buying the policy, after that if you
do it then it will not be applicable and at the same time
if you want to do it by increasing the step count in any wrong way
or by any other way, then
also the insurance company
reserves the right to give you this
benefit. There is another benefit
which is tax rebate, you will get it in the insurance
policy under section 80d of Income
Tax Act, whenever you file your income
tax return, you will have to submit
this receipt to your account.  By giving the receipt of health insurance policy,
you can get rebate in your income tax
under section 80d. Now
friends, I have told you
what things will be covered, when will they be covered,
how much loss will be covered and how
you have to use those features. Now I will
tell you which treatments will
not be covered. If you are
buying this policy thinking of any of these treatments, then
you should not buy it. The first thing
is other treatments before their waiting
period, that is, I had told you that every
disease is not covered from the first day,
whatever its waiting period is, like fever is of
30 days, accident is covered from the first day,
slow growing sequence
diseases like these will be covered after 2 years and
priesting diseases will be covered after 3 years.
If
you file any claim before these time frames, it is
related to treatment whose waiting period is
not over yet, the
company will reject your claim and that
treatment will be rejected.
Secondly, drug abuse, if the patient is suffering from
alcohol abuse or any drug  If
he has been admitted due to addiction or the problem in his body part
is due to alcoholism or any drug abuse and
the doctor specifies that
he has the problem due to this addiction, then this
policy will not cover that treatment also. Next
is pregnancy or dental treatment. See,
maternity is not covered in this. There is
no mention of maternity anywhere in this plan. So
if you want to cover your maternity, then that will
not be covered in this plan.
If any claim comes related to any pregnancy, then this plan will
not cover it. Next is dental treatment, that is,
if you want to get something done related to dental treatment and
want to get coverage, that too will not be covered in this plan.
If during an accident,
dental surgery has to be done, then that is
applicable in this, but normal
dental surgery like RCT or
any other type of modification
treatment will not be covered in this.
Next is act of four nuclear attack
or radiation. These are activities like this which
affect a large population.
Even in these cases, if a war breaks out and
any injury occurs,
Apollo will not cover it.
In case of a nuclear attack or radiation, the company will
not cover it because it
affects people on a large scale.
Health insurance policies do not cover such events.
And the final point is
cosmetic surgeries. If you
want to beautify your face or make cosmetic
changes to your face, then that is
not a medical treatment; it is being done for your hobby and
your choice. The
insurance policy will not cover non-
allopathic treatments, that is, treatments in
their category that are not allopathic treatments.
You can visit the company's website to know the details and exclusions.
However, for your reference,
I have also added the browser in the description.
You can also read the remaining terms and conditions in the procedure. Now,
friends, I have told you about HDFC EGO Optima
Rest Aeroplane.
I have given you the complete details.
Still, if there is any point about which
you want to ask some questions or there is any
point which you feel that I have
not been able to explain in this video,
please you can ask me in the comment section.
I will be very happy to answer your comments.
So friends, if you
liked the video, liked the content and
understood this plan, then you
must subscribe to the channel. And
before buying any health insurance policy,
if you understand the plan properly, then this is my
promise to you that going forward, the plan will not meet
your expectations about that plan.
But see, I
told you earlier that the responsibility is
ours because it is our asset and
we have to take care of it, so I have
bought my health insurance policy after thinking carefully.
I, Harvinder Singh, take your permission.
I will meet you next week
with the most important updates and information. Till then, take
care of yourself, stay happy and
stay healthy. Jai Hind
[Music]